kaplan.co.uk 2017-06-12

# Privacy & Cookie Policy

This is the privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") for Kaplan Financial Limited, part of the Kaplan family of educational companies.

This Privacy Policy describes how we treat personal data received about you when you visit the Kaplan Financial Limited website or otherwise. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, because by visiting or using this site or contracting with us, you agree to its terms. This Privacy Policy applies only to this website and associated mobile applications, and not to the web sites of other Kaplan companies.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any important changes by posting a notice on all Privacy Policy links. If you see a notice of change, please check the Privacy Policy, because your continued use of the site after we post the change means you have agreed to the new terms.

## Collection of your personal data

We collect your personal data when you ask for information about our courses or study materials, when you submit your answers to our assessment quizzes or surveys, when you enrol in one of our courses or order study materials.

To process your enquiries and assessment quizzes or surveys, we collect your name, email and postal addresses, daytime phone number, and, if applicable, company and type of business.

To process enrolments and orders, we ask for your name, email and postal addresses, daytime phone number, company name and address, training manager's name, mobile and home telephone numbers, date of birth, professional certification or registration information, if any, and credit or debit card information.

In addition, the mobile applications may collect certain information automatically, including, but not limited to, the type of mobile device you use, your mobile devices unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use the applications.

We and other Kaplan companies may also use your postal and email addresses to send you information about further professional training, and other services or products similar to those you have ordered from us, or to send you an invitation to solicit such information from our sibling Kaplan educational companies. If you do not wish us to send you this additional information, you can let us know by following the opt-out instructions that we include in every email, or by sending us notice of your preferences through the mechanisms listed in the section below entitled Your Ability to Choose.

## Sharing your data

We will need to use your data to perform our obligations and exercise our rights under agreements made with you and to inform you of feedback and exam results.

If you have enrolled in our courses through your employer, we will share your data and course attendance and test results with your employer.

If you enrol in any of our programmes, we will share your data with AAT, ACCA and CIMA. Please note that this is limited to sharing individual data only with the relevant institution.

We may disclose personal and other data we collect from you in the following ways: 

  * **Service Providers**. We may hire other companies to perform services on our behalf including, without limitation, carrying out market research, facilitating some aspects of our Site and services, managing our database, contacting you, sending e-mail and fulfilling your requests. These other companies may be supplied with or have access to your personal data solely for the purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf. Kaplan is the data controller and will remain accountable for the personal information.
  * **Kaplan Affiliates**. We also may share your data with other business divisions and subsidiaries of Kaplan, Inc. (our "Affiliated Businesses") that provide services we think might interest you.
  * **Business Transfers**. Kaplan may in its sole discretion, transfer, sell or assign your personal data to a third party in connection with a change in the corporate structure of Kaplan such as, but not limited to, merger, consolidation, sale, liquidation, or transfer of substantial assets.
  * **Others**. We may disclose personal information, as permitted or required by law, and to: (i) respond to inquiries or requests from governmental or public authorities; (ii) protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Kaplan; (iii) permit us to pursue available remedies or limit damages that we may sustain; and (iv) enforce our agreements, including without limitation our enrolment terms and conditions.

## Transfer of your data outside your country

As we are an international business with employees, affiliates and service providers all over the world, please note that the personal data you provide to us may be transferred to and processed and stored in the United States or other countries, including without limitation your home country, the country in which you plan to matriculate or other countries where Kaplan, Inc. has offices. Although the data protection laws of these various countries may not be as comprehensive as those in your own country, Kaplan will take appropriate steps to ensure that personal data is handled as described in this Policy. By providing personal data and other information to us, you understand and consent to the collection, use, processing, disclosure and transfer of such personal data to the United States and other countries where Kaplan, Inc. has offices and service providers.

## Your ability to choose

As mentioned above, we may use your email or postal address to send you information on obtaining or maintaining your professional qualification, or other services or products we or other Kaplan companies think might interest you. We also may share your data with other Kaplan companies. If you do not wish to receive such information from us or other Kaplan companies, or you do not wish us to share your data in this manner, you can let us know by [emailing us](mailto:privacy@kaplan.co.uk), updating your details in the Preference Centre or sending your request by post to:

Attention: Privacy Inquiry  
Kaplan Financial Limited Ltd  
179-191 Borough High St,  
London,  
SE1 1HR

## Data registration

Pursuant to the Data Protection Act of 1998, Kaplan Financial Limited has registered as a Data Controller with the United Kingdom Information Commissioner.

## Review and correction

You may review and update the personal data you have provided to us by emailing us at [privacy@kaplan.co.uk](mailto:privacy@kaplan.co.uk "privacy"), or sending your request by post to:

Attention: Privacy Inquiry  
Kaplan Financial Limited Ltd  
179-191 Borough High St,  
London,  
SE1 1HR

## Privacy and cookies

**What is a cookie?**  
A cookie is a simple text file that is stored on your computer or mobile device by a website's server. Only that server will be able to retrieve or read the contents of that cookie. Each cookie is unique to your web browser. It will contain some anonymous information such as a unique identifier as well as the site name. Cookies may be set by the website you are visiting ("first party cookies") or they may be set by other websites who run content on the page you are viewing ("third party cookies").

**How are cookies used?**  
Cookies do lots of different jobs, including letting you navigate between pages efficiently, storing your preferences, and generally improving your experience of a website. Most websites you visit will use cookies to improve your user experience by enabling that website to "remember" you, either for the duration of your visit (using a "session cookie") or for repeat visits (using a "persistent cookie").

If a website doesn't use cookies, it will think you are a visiting the website for the first time every time you move to a new page on the site - for example, when you enter your login details and move to another page the website won't recognise you and it won't be able to keep you logged in.

Some websites will also use cookies to enable them to target their advertising or marketing messages based, for example, on your location and/or browsing habits.

**Categories of cookies**  
The cookies used by our website, or that will be used in the future, are classified as follows:

  * Strictly necessary
  * Performance
  * Functionality
  * Targeting

Explanations of each category and the cookies that Kaplan Financial Limited uses in each category are detailed next.

**Strictly necessary**  
Some cookies are strictly necessary in order to enable you to move around the website and fully use its features. Without these cookies, we will not be able to provide certain features, such as automatically signing in to protected areas.

| **Name of Cookie** | **Description**  
---|---  
**Ecommerce** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses EcommerceSSO, EcommerceSSO1, FedAuth and FedAuth1 to maintain your user session whilst you are completing a purchase.  
**StsSiteCookie** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses StsSiteCookie **,** which is an authentication cookie stored on the users machine to determine if they are already logged in and sends user back to the SharePoint site.  
**ASP.NET** | The **Kaplan Financial Ltd** website uses ASP.NET to allow web servers to respond to your actions on the website. The website wouldn't work for you without it.  
  
**Performance**  
Performance cookies can be used to help us provide you with a better user experience. Information supplied by these cookies helps us to understand how our visitors use the Kaplan Financial Limited website so that we can improve how we present our content to you. They also allow us to test different design ideas for particular pages, such as the Kaplan Financial Limited homepage. We generally contract with independent measurement and research companies to perform these services for us and when this is the case, these cookies may be set by a third party company (third party cookies).

**Name of Cookie** | **Description**  
---|---  
**Google Analytics** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses Google Analytics. This is a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie in order to evaluate use of those services and compile a report for us. User data is anonymous.

[Opt-out of Google Analytics cookies](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "Opt-out of Google Analytics cookies").  
  
**Reevoo Mark** | 

Used for Reevoo Analytics (web analytics service provided by Reevoo) which tracks customer interaction with review widgets on the **Kaplan Financial Limited** site. Also enables us to compile reports about user behaviour. User data is anonymous. Expires after 1 month.

[Reevoo Privacy Policy](http://www.reevoo.com/privacy-policy "Reevoo Privacy Policy").  
  
**Reevoo Session** | 

Used for Google Analytics web analytics on the Kaplan Financial Ltd website, which uses a cookie to evaluate use of these services and compile a report for us. User data is anonymous. Expires when your browsing session ends.

[Reevoo Privacy Policy](http://www.reevoo.com/privacy-policy "Reevoo Privacy Policy").  
  
**Functionality**  
Functionality cookies record information about choices you've made and allow us to tailor the website to you. For example, we may use cookies to save your location preference. Functionality cookies may also take the form of Flash cookies, which are stored in your Adobe Flash Player rather than on your web browser.

**Name of Cookie** | **Description**  
---|---  
**Kampyle** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses Kampyle to collect feedback on product pages, helping us to excel in online lead generation, optimise our landing pages and overcome form abandonment.

[Opt-out of Kampyle cookies](http://www.kampyle.com/enterprise/company/privacy-policy).  
  
**Targeting**  
A certain amount of our advertising is tailored to the individual user. We use cookies to work out what advertising might be most relevant to you, based on the areas you look at on our sites and your IP address geo-location. The table below provides links to the individual ad serving partners opt-out mechanisms:

**Name of Cookie** | **Description**  
---|---  
**DoubleClick** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses Doubleclick cookies. These are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements you click on and interact with. Each individual advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken is not confidential or interchangeable.

**Google Remarketing** | The **Kaplan Financial Limited** website uses Remarketing cookies. Google Remarketing allows us and our advertisers to advertise relevant information to users. Remarketing cookie lists are stored in a database on Google's servers, which store all the cookie IDs associated with each list.

**Embedded content**  
To support our content, we sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube, Twitter, Facebook and Wufoo. As a result, when you visit a page containing such content, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. Kaplan Financial Limited does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party's website for more information.

**Sharing tools**  
You will also see embedded "share" buttons on the Kaplan Financial Limited web pages; these enable users to easily share content with their friends through a number of popular social networks. When you click on one of these buttons, a cookie may be set by the service you have chosen to share content through. Kaplan Financial Limited does not control the dissemination of these cookies. Examples currently on our website include:

**What to do if you don't want cookies to be set?**  
If you prefer, it is possible to block some or all cookies or even to delete cookies that have already been set; but you need to be aware that you might lose some functions of that website. To do this, please follow the instructions below which outline "how to turn off cookies on your browser". There are also instructions in each category of cookies above which give information on how to opt out of some individually, for example Google Analytics.

**How to turn off cookies on your web browser for all websites**  
All recent versions of popular browsers give users a level of control over cookies.

Users can set their browsers to accept or reject all, or certain, cookies. Users can also set their browser to prompt them each time a cookie is offered. The main browser types and instructions on how to turn off cookies for ALL sites, not just Kaplan Financial Limited, are available on the [**aboutcookies.org**](http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1 "About Cookies") website.

We recommend that if you do find the use of cookies intrusive that you follow the instructions on this website and turn them off for all websites, not just for Kaplan Financial Limited.

## If you would like to find out more information about cookies:

**Information Commissioner's Office**  
The [Information Commissioner's Office](http://www.ico.gov.uk/ "ICO") is the UK’s independent authority set up to uphold information rights in the public interest, promoting openness by public bodies and data privacy for individuals.

**Information about cookies**  
Useful information about cookies can be found at aboutcookies.org.

**Internet Advertising Bureau**  
A guide to behavioural advertising and online privacy has been produced by the [Internet Advertising Industry](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "Internet Advertising Industry").

**International Chamber of Commerce United Kingdom**  
Information on the ICC (UK) UK cookie guide can be found on the ICC website section

 **Kaplan Financial Limited, company number 01028790, registered office address 179-191 Borough High St,London, SE1 1HR**
